Guide to the Abu Dhabi Film Festival Collection 2007-2014 AD.MC.006
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
Abu Dhabi Film Festival Collection
1940-2014
2007-2014
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.MC.006
20 Linear Feet 150 DVDs
The Abu Dhabi Film Festival Collection includes DVD copies of many films screened over the course of the festival's 2007-2014 run and ephemera related to the festival. The films represent the different sections of each festival as well as the work of local and international filmmakers.
Biographical / Historical
The Abu Dhabi Film Festival began in 2007 as the Middle East International Film Festival, rebranding itself in 2009. Since its inception, the festival's mission has been to foster a "vibrant film culture throughout the region." As part of this aim, ADFF worked to curate "exceptional international programmes to engage and educate the local community, inspire young filmmakers from the region and nurture the growth of the regional film industry." The annual event incorporated a variety of programs into the festival, including film screenings and competitions, galas, talks, workshops, and master classes. As represented by the films in this collection, the festival was international in nature. Many of the films though come from local or regional filmmakers (UAE and GCC) who competed in the festival's Emirates Film Competition. A portion of those filmmakers are amateur, part-time, or novice filmmakers. The festival was closed down after the 2014 iteration, with support for local and regional filmmakers continuing through the Sanad Abu Dhabi Film Fund.
http://www.sanadfilmfund.com/en/Images/ADFF14-guide-English_tcm14-20554.pdf http://www.thenational.ae/uae/abu-dhabi-film-festival-to-be-closed-down
Arrangement
The collection is organized chronologically by festival year. Within each annual version of the festival, the films are organized by the categories and competitions they were presented in at the festival, and within the categories they are organized alphabetically.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains DVD copies of films screened at the Abu Dhabi Film Festival from its first festival in 2007 to the final one in 2014. The films represented in the collection come from the different competitions, showcases, and presentations from each of the versions of the festival; the national, regional, and international films are both documentary and fiction (narrative) in both short and feature length. The collection is made up of works that were made for submission to the festival, or were screened at many film festivals that year, as well as older films that were presented as part of showcases and retrospectives. Along with the films, the collection contains ephemera and publications (guides, brochures) from the festival.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers. For more information contact nyuad-asc-group@nyu.edu.
Custodial History
The films in the collection were acquired from the filmmakers or purchased from various commercial outlets by the NYU Abu Dhabi Library Archives and Special Collections. The accompanying archival material was collected by the library or acquired by donation.
- 2009 Abu Dhabi Film Festival
  - Documentary Competition
    - All My Mothers, 2008 (Disk ADFF 2009-11)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Original Format: Digital Betacam
      Color
      Total Running Time: 00:60:00
      Details:
      Directors: Ebrahim Saeedi, Sahavi Sanjavi (Iran, Iraq)
      Original Title: Hamey-e Madaran-e Man
      Catalog Record: GetIt | All My Mothers
      More Information
    - Goodbye, How Are You?, 2009 (Disk ADFF 2009-4)
      Director: Boris Mitic (Serbia)
      Original Title: Dovidjenja, kako ste?
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Goodbye, How Are You?
    - On the Way to School, 2008 (Disk ADFF 2009-3)
      Original Format: 35mm
      Total Running Time: 01:21:00
      Directors: Orhan Eskiloy, Ozgur Dogan
      Original Title: Iki Dil Bir Bavul
      Catalog Record: GetIt | On the Way to School
  - Narrative Competition
    - Third Person Singular Number, 2009 (Disk ADFF 2009-9)
      Total Running Time: 02:03:00
      Director: Mostofa Sarwar Farooki (Bangladesh)
      Original Title: Third Person Singular Number
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Third Person Singular Number
  - New Cinema from Turkey
    - Dot, 2009 (Disk ADFF 2009-18)
      Total Running Time: 01:18:00
      Director: Dervis Zaim (Turkey)
      Original Title: Nokta
      Catalog record: GetIt | Dot
    - Milk, 2008 (Disk 2009-19)
      Total Running Time: 01:42:00
      Director: Semih Kaplanoglu
      Original Title: Süt
      Catalog Record: Currently unavailable
  - Shorts Competition
    - Ata, 2008 (Disk ADFF 2009-10)
      Total Running Time: 00:26:00
      Directors: Cagla Zencirci, Guillaume Giovanetti
      Original Title: Ata
      Catalog Record: Get It | Ata
    - Diplomacy, 2009 (Disk ADFF 2009-14)
      Original Format: HDCAM
      Total Running Time: 00:09:00
      Director: Jon Goldman (USA)
      Original Title: Diplomacy
      Catalog Record: Get It| Diplomacy
    - The Employment, 2008 (Disk ADFF 2009-17)
      Total Running Time: 00:06:00
      Director: Santiago 'Bou' Grasso
      Original Title: El Empleo
      Catalog Record: Get It | The Employment
    - Fatenah, 2009 (Disk ADFF 2009-16)
      Originial Format: Digital Betacam
      Total Running Time: 00:30:00
      Director: Ahmad Habash (Palestine)
      Original Title: Fatenah
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Fatenah
    - Glory at Sea, 2008 (Disk ADFF 2009-6)
      Total Running Time: 00:25:00
      Director: Benh Zeitlin (USA)
      Original Title: Glory at Sea
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Glory at Sea
    - Home, 2009 (Disk ADFF 2009-8)
      Director: Matt Faust (USA)
      Original Title: Home
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Home
    - Walls, 2009 (Disk ADFF 2009-7)
      Director: Mohammed Saad Jasim (Iraq)
      Original Title: Walls
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Walls
  - Student Shorts
    - Kasia, 2008 (Disk ADFF 2009-15)
      Total Running Time: 00:10:00
      Director: Elisabet Llado (Belgium)
      Original Title: Kaisa
      Catalog Record: Currently unavaliable
    - Our Neck of the Woods, 2009 (Disk ADFF 2009-2)
      Total Running Time: 00:17:00
      Director: Rob Connolly (USA)
      Original Title: Our Neck of the Woods
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Our Neck of the Woods
    - Schautag, 2008 (Disk ADFF 2009-13)
      Total Running Time: 00:23:00
      Director: Marvin Kren (Germany)
      Original Title: Schautag
      Catalog Record: GetIT | Schautag
    - Surprise, 2008 (Disk ADFF 2009-12)
      Total Running Time: 00:21:00
      Director: Elena Bychkova (Russia)
      Original Title: Surpriz
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Surprise
    - Under Construction, 2009 (Disk ADFF 2009-5)
      Total Running Time: 00:29:00
      Director: Damien Dufresne (France)
      Original Title: Chantier
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Under Construction
  - What in the World are We Doing to our World?
    - The Gift of Pachamama, 2008 (Disk ADFF 2009-1)
      Director: Toshifumi Matsushita
      Original Title: El regalo de la pachamama
      Catalog Record: GetIt |The Gift of Pachamama
- 2010 Abu Dhabi Film Festival
  - Emirates Film Competition
    - Aseel, 2010 (Disk ADFF 2010-17)
      Original Format: MiniDV
      Total Running Time: 00:15:00
      Director: Faisal Al-Harbi (Saudi Arabia)
      Original Title: Aseel
      Catalog Record: Get It | Aseel
    - Father Grant, 2010 (Disk ADFF 2010-20)
      Total Running Time: 00:13:00
      Details
      Director: Ahmed Zain (UAE)
      Original Title: Menhat Al-Waled
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Father Grant
    - Gheamt Shroog, 2010 (Disk ADFF 2010-18)
      Total Running Time: 00:16:00
      Original Title: Gheamt Shroog
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Gheamt Shroog
    - Leap of Faith, 2010 (Disk ADFF 2010-4)
      Director: Amna Ehtesham Khaishgi (UAE)
      Original Title: Qafzat Al-Iman
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Leap of Faith
    - A Sketch of a Life in the UAE, 2010 (Disk ADFF 2009-19)
      Total Running Time: 00:12:00
      Director: Shoko Okurano
      Original Title: Fasel min Al-Hayat
      Catalog Record: GetIt | A Sketch of a Life in the UAE
- 2011 Abu Dhabi Film Festival
  - Emirates Film Competition
    - Darkness, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-34)
      Total Running Time: 00:18:00
      Director: Ahmed Zain (United Arab Emirates
      Arabic
      Original Title: Atma
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Darkness
      More Info
    - Halfway, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-33)
      Color, Black and White
      Director: Mohammed Mamdouh (United Arab Emirates)
      Arabic, English
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Halfway
    - Igrab, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-37)
      Total Running Time: 00:20:00
      Director: Hamad Saghran (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Igrab
    - Kingdom of Women, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-8)
      Director: Amna Ehtesham Khaishgi (Pakistan)
      Urdu
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Kingdom Of Women
    - Lahjatna (Our Accent), 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-9)
      Director: Mariam Al Nuaimi (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Lahjatna (Our Accent)
    - Layers, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-10)
      Total Running Time: 00:07:00
      Director: Manal Wicki (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Layers
    - Mad Camel, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-20)
      Total Running Time: 00:05:00
      Director: Mohammad Fikree (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Mad Camel
    - A Night to Remember, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-32)
      Director: Fahmi Farahat (Saudi Arabia)
      Original Title: Laylat Omr
      Catalog Record: GetIt | A Night To Remember
    - Photon, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-19)
      Director: Awadh Al Hamzani (Saudi Arabia)
      Arabic, English, Swedish
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Photon
    - Sa'eed, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-31)
      Total Running Time: 00:02:00
      Director: Marwan Al Hammadi (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Sa'eed
    - Sons of the Sun, 2010 (Disk ADFF 2011-24)
      Total Running Time: 00:35:00
      Director: Ahmed Abdelnasser (Qatar)
      Catlog Record: GetIt | Sons Of The Sun
    - Soul, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-36)
      Director: Fatma Abdullah (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Soul
    - Swing, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-30)
      Director: Abdullah Al Daihani (Kuwait)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Swing
    - Telephoni, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2011-29)
      Total Running Time: 00:08:00
      Director: Hassan Kiyany (United Arab Emirates)
      Arabic, Hindi
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Telephoni
- 2012 Abu Dhabi Film Festival
  - Emirates Film Competition
    - Cats, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-56)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Cats
    - Children, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-41)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Children
    - The Final Division, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-42)
      Black and White
      Director: Hana Kazim (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Final Division
    - Foresight, 2011 (Disk ADFF 2012-59)
      Total Running Time: 00:33:00
      Director: Ahmed Zain, Naser Al Yagobi (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Baseera
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Foresight
    - Frozen Yogurt, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-60)
      Total Running Time: 00:14:00
      Director: Ahmed Zain (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Laban Mothallaj
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Frozen Yogurt
    - The Gamboo3a Revolution, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-25)
      Deatils:
      Director: Abdulrahman Al Madani (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Gamboo3a Revolution
    - The Journey, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-55)
      Director: Hana Makki (United Arab Emirates)
      English
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Journey
    - Murk Light, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-12)
      Director: Yassir Al Yassiri (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Titlw: Daw' Daames
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Murk Light
    - The Orphanage, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-58)
      Director: Mohammed Al Otaiba (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Orphanage
    - Ostora, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-11)
      Original Format: DCP
      Director: Hani Kichi (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Ostora
    - Patience Salt, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-47)
      Director: Mohammed Ibrahim (Bahrain)
      Original Title: Sabr Al Melh
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Patience Salt
    - Smaller than the Sky, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-57)
      Director: Abdulla Hassan Ahmed (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Smaller Than The Sky
    - Three Dolls and a Paper Plane, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2012-14)
      Total Running Time: 00:03:00
      Director: Hend Al Fahad (Saudi Arabia)
      Original Title: Thalath 'Araaes W Taaera Waraqeiya
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Three Dolls And A Paper Plane
- 2013 Abu Dhabi Film Festival
  - Documentary Competition (Disk Unknown container 12 for instance of Documentary Competition)
    No Subnote Content
    Scope and Contents
    - Doctor Fabre Will Cure You, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-60)
      Total Running Time: 01:01:00
      Director: Pierre Coulibeuf (Belgium, France)
      Dutch, English, French
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Doctor Fabre Will Cure You
    - El Gort, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-50)
      Total Running Time: 01:26:00
      Director: Hamza Aouni (Tunisia, United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Jamal al-barrouta
      Catalog Record: GetIt | El Gort
    - InRealLife, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-27)
      Director: Beeban Kidron (United Kingdom)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | InRealLife
    - My Stolen Revolution, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-6)
      Total Running Time: 01:15:00
      Director: Nahid Persson Sarvestani (Sweden)
      Farsi, Swedish
      Catalog Record: GetIt | My Stolen Revolution
    - Sacro GRA, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-48)
      Total Running Time: 01:33:00
      Director: Gianfranco Rosi (Italy)
      Italian
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Sacro GRA
    - School of Babel, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-44)
      Total Running Time: 01:30:00
      Director: Julie Bertuccelli (France)
      French
      Original Title: La Cour de Babel
      Catalog Record: GetIt | School Of Babel
    - Whispers of the Cities, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-54)
      Total Running Time: 01:02:00
      Director: Kasim Abid (Iraq, United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Hams al-mudan
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Whispers Of The Cities
  - Emirates Film Competition
    - Against the Wind, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2013-57)
      Director: Aisha Abdullah (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Dhid al reeh
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Against The Wind
    - Bader, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2013-53)
      Director: Sara Al-Saadi, Maaria Assami, Latifa Al-Darwish (Qatar)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Bader
    - Daddy ABC, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2013-69)
      Original Format:HDCAM
      Director: Hamad Alawar (United Arab Emirates)
      (None)
      Original Title: Abjadiyat al ubuwa
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Daddy ABC
    - Feeding Five Hundred, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2013-56)
      Total Running Time: 00:22:00
      Director: Rafed Al-Harthi, Ray Haddad (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Itaa'm khams miya
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Feeding Five Hundred
    - Guilt, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-41)
      Director: Abdulrahman Al Madani (United Arabi Emirates)
      Original Title: Dhanb
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Guilt
    - Happy Birthday Younis, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-70)
      Original Title: Eid milad Younis
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Happy Birthday Younis
    - Ice, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-71)
      Director: Omar Ibrahim (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Thalj
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Ice
    - Marionette, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-58)
      Total Running Time: 00:04:00
      Director: Sophia Jawad (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Marionette al duma al mutaharika
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Marionette
    - Men Subdue, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2013-26)
      Director: Saeed Almas (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Qahar al rijal
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Men Subdue
    - Mirror, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-52)
      Director: Ameera Madhi (United Arab Emirates)
      Original Title: Maraa'
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Mirror
    - My Pink Room, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-66)
      Director: Vachan Sharma (Kuwait)
      Original Title: Ghurfati zahriyat al lawn
      Catalog Record: GetIt | My Pink Room
    - Safi, 2012 (Disk ADFF 2013-68)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Safi
    - The Taxi Driver, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-55)
      Director: Shaddad Musalmy (Oman)
      Original Title: Saii'q Taxi
      Catalog Record: GetIt | The Taxi Driver
    - With Time, 2013 (Disk ADFF 2013-67)
      Director: Malak Quota (United Arab Emirates, Saudi Arabia)
      Original Title: Maa' al zaman
      Catalog Record: GetIt | With Time
- 2014 Abu Dhabi Film Festival
  - Emirates Film Competition
    - Cholo, 2014 (Disk ADFF 2014-26)
      Original Format: Blu Ray
      Director: Muzna Al-Musafer (Oman)
      Swahili
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Cholo
    - Don't Leave Me, 2014 (Disk ADFF 2014-16)
      Director: Khalid Al Mahmood (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Don't Leave Me
    - Girl & It, 2014 (Disk ADFF 2014-40)
      Original Format: HDCAM SR
      Total Running Time: 00:40:00
      Director: Mohammed Fikree (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Girl & It
    - Kings and Queens of Qatar, 2014 (Disk ADFF 2014-35)
      Director: Shamir Allibhai (Qatar)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | King And Queens Of Qatar
    - Koshk, 2014 (Disk ADFF 2014-37)
      Director: Abdulla Al Kaabi (United Arab Emirates)
      Farsi
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Koshk
    - Nagafa, 2014 (Disk ADFF 2014-34)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Nagafa
    - Now Showing, 2014 (Disk ADFF 2014-1)
      Total Running Time: 00:19:00
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Now Showing
    - Shadows, 2014 (Disk ADFF 2014-38)
      Total Running Time: 0012:00
      Director: Mohamed Magdy (United Arab Emirates)
      Catalog Record: GetIt | Shadows